<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opinions on Jesús Pérez</title>
    <link>https://masher2.github.io/categories/opinions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opinions on Jesús Pérez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://masher2.github.io/categories/opinions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe&#39;s Venezuela ban and why libre software is the solution</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2019/10/adobe-s-venezuela-ban-and-why-libre-software-is-the-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2019/10/adobe-s-venezuela-ban-and-why-libre-software-is-the-solution/</guid>
      <description>On October 7th there was an announcement by the proprietary software giant Adobe to ban al Venezuelan users from using any of its services, not even giving them a refund.1 Such announcement came seemingly out of nowhere, following an executive order that doesn’t really impede them from having business relationships with individual venezuelan citizens but with the “Goverment of Venezuela”.
The implications of such action are absolutely detrimental, as most of the creative workers use or depend on Adobe software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crypto, banking, and spending money in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2019/08/crypto-banking-and-spending-money-in-venezuela/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2019/08/crypto-banking-and-spending-money-in-venezuela/</guid>
      <description>Today I saw Universal Access to Basic Finance by Andreas M. Antonopoulos, he starts the talk saying that when visiting Argentina in 2013 for the first time he didn’t need to explain “why, why bitcoin, why open blockchains, why freedom of finance”, that is because all the people in the conference room were interested in the “how”, because they already understanded the “why”; those opening words struck me, because here in Venezuela, at least in the kind of environment I am and the kind of people I know, most of us already know the “why”: The Bolivar Soberano (VES).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>