<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Podcast on Jesús Pérez</title>
    <link>https://masher2.github.io/tags/podcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Podcast on Jesús Pérez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://masher2.github.io/tags/podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 13</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-13/</guid>
      <description>This week was the definition of dead. Here is the only thing worth sharing that I saw this week and the corresponding music recommendation.
 [podcast] Private Suite Podcast : Vapor Memory Interview: This was an incredible find, I didn’t know there was a podcast dedicated to vaporwave until Vapor Memory uploaded this interview on his channel.
Being the go-to channel to discover vaporwave on youtube, Vapor Memory is a very well known name in the vaporwave community, a name I would say as well known as some of the older and well established vaporwave artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 12</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-12/</guid>
      <description>This week I played Hellblade: Senua’s sacrifice, I was interested in this game because it’s an adventure seen through a schizophrenic woman’s eyes, there are visual artifacts through the game and voices, friendly and hostile, that whisper, speak and scream to you from all directions, as if they come from inside your mind, all to make you feel immersed in the experience of living as a schizophrenic. It was a short game but deeply engaging, it truly is a story that is best told through an interactive medium like videogames.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>