<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jesús Pérez</title>
    <link>https://masher2.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jesús Pérez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://masher2.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 2</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/04/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/04/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-2/</guid>
      <description>This was a slow week, between my internet being at the absolute worst speed possible and almost all my free time spent playing Digimon Story: Cyber Sleuth (DSCS) on my Nintendo Switch I didn’t manage to find much, nontheless here are a few interesting things that I thought worth sharing.
 [blog post] “It’s collapsing violently”: Coronavirus is creating a fast fashion nightmare: An interview with Dana Thomas about the impact of coronavirus in the fast fashion industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 1</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/03/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/03/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week/</guid>
      <description>I had been planning to blog more but I haven’t had the motivation to do so, so instead of focusing all my mental energy into a single topic that I just didn’t have so much to talk about or doing a project that really wasn’t as fun as I thought it could be I will be sharing here a few interesting things (and my comments on some of those things) that I have seen on a weekly basis (hopefully).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a data pipeline in R for streaming tweets</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2019/11/writing-a-data-pipeline-in-r-for-streaming-tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2019/11/writing-a-data-pipeline-in-r-for-streaming-tweets/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by this datacamp post and the current events happening in Chile I decided to give it a try to make my own version of a tweet streaming script, with the intention of using it when another event of that magnitud happens and maybe getting some useful insights then, or maybe not, at least I had fun while doing this.
Setting up the structure of the script The first thing I did was plan how to structure the script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe&#39;s Venezuela ban and why libre software is the solution</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2019/10/adobe-s-venezuela-ban-and-why-libre-software-is-the-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2019/10/adobe-s-venezuela-ban-and-why-libre-software-is-the-solution/</guid>
      <description>On October 7th there was an announcement by the proprietary software giant Adobe to ban al Venezuelan users from using any of its services, not even giving them a refund.1 Such announcement came seemingly out of nowhere, following an executive order that doesn’t really impede them from having business relationships with individual venezuelan citizens but with the “Goverment of Venezuela”.
The implications of such action are absolutely detrimental, as most of the creative workers use or depend on Adobe software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crypto, banking, and spending money in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2019/08/crypto-banking-and-spending-money-in-venezuela/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2019/08/crypto-banking-and-spending-money-in-venezuela/</guid>
      <description>Today I saw Universal Access to Basic Finance by Andreas M. Antonopoulos, he starts the talk saying that when visiting Argentina in 2013 for the first time he didn’t need to explain “why, why bitcoin, why open blockchains, why freedom of finance”, that is because all the people in the conference room were interested in the “how”, because they already understanded the “why”; those opening words struck me, because here in Venezuela, at least in the kind of environment I am and the kind of people I know, most of us already know the “why”: The Bolivar Soberano (VES).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Jesús Pérez, a statistician graduated from the UCV (Universidad Central de Venezuela) in 2018. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in data science, cryptocurrencies, libre software and ｖａｐｏｒｗａｖｅ.
I&amp;rsquo;m not an expert in any field so I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting about whatever new I learn that would be nice to share and interesting things I find in the internet.
@ or DM me on twitter if you want @masher_2, I&amp;rsquo;m not active but maybe I will.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>