<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on Jesús Pérez</title>
    <link>https://masher2.github.io/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on Jesús Pérez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://masher2.github.io/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 20</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/08/interesting-thigs-i-saw-this-week-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/08/interesting-thigs-i-saw-this-week-20/</guid>
      <description>This week is a short one, I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to say and also spent most of the week without internet (third world&amp;rsquo;s nice AMIRITE).
[podcast] #620: How to Deal With Life’s Regrets A podcast discussing the concept of counterfactual thinking, what it is, how it affects our lives and some other things related to it.
[blog-post] Politics matters most to slaves. In this post Luke Smith explains why he usually doesn&amp;rsquo;t talk about politics in his youtube channel or in his website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Things I saw This week - 19</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/08/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/08/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-19/</guid>
      <description>[blog-post] Navigating the internet as a non-binary designer This one caught me by surprise, the problems of gender nonconforming people are something that never crosses my mind as I don&amp;rsquo;t know nor interact with any in my daily life. I came across this post on twitter the other day and thought it would be nice to read as I really don&amp;rsquo;t know much about it and it is always nice to see how people can have completely diferent experiences from yours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 18</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/07/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/07/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-18/</guid>
      <description>[blog-post] Our history is a battle against the microbes: we lost terribly before science, public health, and vaccines allowed us to protect ourselves A data-backed post showing how much infectious diseases affected us during our history and how vaccines helped us in our struggle for survival.
This post comes in a time most opportune, as more and more people are concerned with the effects and motivations behind vaccination, serving as a reminder that without vaccines the world would be an even dangerous place than it is right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 16</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/07/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/07/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-16/</guid>
      <description>After a few week without any serious reading, I decided to finally finish The Omnivore&amp;rsquo;s Dilemma. Part 4 is about hunting, gathering and gardening food, the least middlemen between you and your food.
Right away I found some points worth discussing, one of the earliest being a remark made that it took ancient hunter-gatherers only about 17 hours a week to hunt and gather enough food for them and their families, compared with the now seemingly universal 40 hour work week it seems that the modern life gives us more things to do and leave us with less time to do them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 15</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/07/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/07/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-15/</guid>
      <description>This week I tinkered with my laptop&amp;rsquo;s graphic configuration, I messed up and had to spent a day working inside a tty, fortunately I am an avid terminal user and could live without a graphical interface and also the same day, albeit almost at midnight, I could fix the problem. Now I can use the Nvidia graphics card that came with my laptop and can peek into the PC master race lifestyle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 14</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-14/</guid>
      <description>[video] Zoomer Consooomer gets Red-pilled on Technology Luke Smith responding to an email asking him about the intersection between technology and life.
In the video, Luke talks about how being aware of the implications of technology in one&amp;rsquo;s life doesn&amp;rsquo;t translate into having to reject everything modernity has to offer, but that being aware of those implications gives you the opportunity to make decisions that limit the negative impact of technology in your life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 13</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-13/</guid>
      <description>This week was the definition of dead. Here is the only thing worth sharing that I saw this week and the corresponding music recommendation.
[podcast] Private Suite Podcast : Vapor Memory Interview This was an incredible find, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know there was a podcast dedicated to vaporwave until Vapor Memory uploaded this interview on his channel.
Being the go-to channel to discover vaporwave on youtube, Vapor Memory is a very well known name in the vaporwave community, a name I would say as well known as some of the older and well established vaporwave artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 12</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-12/</guid>
      <description>This week I played Hellblade: Senua&amp;rsquo;s sacrifice, I was interested in this game because it&amp;rsquo;s an adventure seen through a schizophrenic woman&amp;rsquo;s eyes, there are visual artifacts through the game and voices, friendly and hostile, that whisper, speak and scream to you from all directions, as if they come from inside your mind, all to make you feel immersed in the experience of living as a schizophrenic. It was a short game but deeply engaging, it truly is a story that is best told through an interactive medium like videogames.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 11</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-11/</guid>
      <description>Not much happened this week, I started developing a vim plugin to manage my blog, read a little and continued with Chef&amp;rsquo;s Table; the 1st episode of the 3rd season had me in tears through the whole episode, it was beautiful seeing Jeong Kwan cooking and sharing her story, my favourite chapter yet.
[video] Joe Rogan is wondering what I&amp;rsquo;m hiding! Rob Braxman responding to a comment made by Joe Rogan in the june second episode of Joe Rogan Experience in which while talking about mass surveillance Joe express that he has been following Rob Braxman and wonders why is he so concerned about online privacy, &amp;ldquo;what is he hiding?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 10</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-10/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching Chef&amp;rsquo;s Table, as the name sugests it is about chefs, with each episode being a short documentary about a single chef&amp;rsquo;s history, the restaurants in which they are working and why they are cooking as they are. It is hands down one of the best shows I&amp;rsquo;ve seen.
Dan Barber, the chef featured in the second episode, was the one that most resonated with me; the restaurants he owns revolve around the concept of farm to table, cooking the ingredients as close as posible to the source, all local and sustainable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 9</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-9/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently into the local sustainable section of The omnivore&amp;rsquo;s dilemma, reading about Polyface farm feels like a dream, it&amp;rsquo;s incredible how that way of farming contrasts with the industrial way of highly scaled monocrop fields.
One of the things that came to my mind whilst reading this section was that automation isn&amp;rsquo;t always synonym with progress, even though the industrial food system has skyrocketed the production of food, it has done so despite the damage it causes to the land and the ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 8</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-8/</guid>
      <description>This week I finished the second part of The omnivore&amp;rsquo;s dilemma, the one about the industrial organic food system. Not much changes compared to the plain industrial food system, the main difference stands in the lack of chemical fertilizers and pesticides, but the conditions of everything else, from how fields are distributed and harvested to how animals are kept stays the same, factory farms.
The funny thing about this is the history behind some of the organic agribusinesses opearting in the US, in the book Cascadian Farm is mentiontioned:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 7</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-7/</guid>
      <description>Last week I commented some things about the first few chapters of The omnivore&amp;rsquo;s dilemma, this week I finished reading the first part, the one about the industrial food chain, and there are some more things to be said about it.
In chapter 8 the author talks about how the omnivore&amp;rsquo;s dilemma1 is solved by culture: One eats what one&amp;rsquo;s parents eat, they eat what their parents ate and so on; through generations cultural eating habits are formed, and those habits are generally sufficient to keep most people healthy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 6</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-6/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading The omnivore&amp;rsquo;s dilemma by Michael Pollan lately, the book is a deep dive into how food is produced. It is divided into 4 parts, each one about a way of producing food (Industrial, industrial organical, local sustainable and hunter-gatherer). I am currently at chapter five, still inside the industrial portion of the book and I can tell you it has been unexpected, I had some knowledge about how industrial food is farmed (or more appropiately, manufactured) but there are some things that I find extremely amusing: how, at least in the USA as the book has only talked about it and I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it applies to any other country, the industrial food system is mostly designed around corn, makig it so cheap that all farmers lose money growing it, yet they can&amp;rsquo;t grow any other crops because corn is the only thing bought around their farms and only corn is subsidized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 3</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/04/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/04/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-3/</guid>
      <description>I avoid almost all covid19 information out there in order to mantain my chill during this time, it is stressful enough to have to go outside to buy groceries surrounded by people that don&amp;rsquo;t take this situation seriously, I don&amp;rsquo;t need all my remaining time to be consumed by stress related to unactionable information. Getting that out of the way, this week I read something about why people shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be doing data visualizations lightly with covid19 data, a must read if you work with data and want to make something pretty to display in your linkedin profile.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>