<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Farming on Jesús Pérez</title>
    <link>https://masher2.github.io/tags/farming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Farming on Jesús Pérez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://masher2.github.io/tags/farming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 23</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/08/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/08/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-23/</guid>
      <description>This week I found an amazing zine about open hardware and decentralized software projects. It is offered as a print edition or as a free download here, you should check it out, it&amp;rsquo;s a nice throwback to the experience of reading a magazine, even if it is through a monitor.
[video] Shoshana Zuboff on surveillance capitalism | VPRO Documentary This is one of the most relevant videos that I have seen on the topic of why big tech companies are absolutely awful, everyone needs to see this as Shoshana explains it very well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 18</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/07/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/07/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-18/</guid>
      <description>[blog-post] Our history is a battle against the microbes: we lost terribly before science, public health, and vaccines allowed us to protect ourselves A data-backed post showing how much infectious diseases affected us during our history and how vaccines helped us in our struggle for survival.
This post comes in a time most opportune, as more and more people are concerned with the effects and motivations behind vaccination, serving as a reminder that without vaccines the world would be an even dangerous place than it is right now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>