<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food on Jesús Pérez</title>
    <link>https://masher2.github.io/tags/food/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Food on Jesús Pérez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://masher2.github.io/tags/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 6</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-6/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading The omnivore’s dillema by Michael Pollan lately, the book is a deep dive into how food is produced. It is divided into 4 parts, each one about a way of producing food (Industrial, industrial organical, local sustainable and hunter-gatherer). I am currently at chapter five, still inside the industrial portion of the book and I can tell you it has been unexpected, I had some knowledge about how industrial food is farmed (or more appropiately, manufactured) but there are some things that I find extremely amusing: how, at least in the USA as the book has only talked about it and I don’t know if it applies to any other country, the industrial food system is mostly designed around corn, makig it so cheap that all farmers lose money growing it, yet they can’t grow any other crops because corn is the only thing bought around their farms and only corn is subsidized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 1</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/03/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/03/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week/</guid>
      <description>I had been planning to blog more but I haven’t had the motivation to do so, so instead of focusing all my mental energy into a single topic that I just didn’t have so much to talk about or doing a project that really wasn’t as fun as I thought it could be I will be sharing here a few interesting things (and my comments on some of those things) that I have seen on a weekly basis (hopefully).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>