<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Jesús Pérez</title>
        <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Jesús Pérez</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://masher2.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 17</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/07/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-17/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/07/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-17/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>This week I freed (i.e. open sourced) a <a href="https://github.com/masher2/freebitbot" target="_blank">bot that claimed the reward from frebitco.in automatically</a>, it served me for over a year but as I withdrew everything from the page I no longer care if anybody uses it.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="blog-post-high-quality-gif-with-ffmpeg-http-blog-pkh-me-p-21-high-quality-gif-with-ffmpeg-html"><a href="http://blog.pkh.me/p/21-high-quality-gif-with-ffmpeg.html" target="_blank">[blog-post] High quality GIF with FFmpeg</a></h4>

<p>A quick post that teaches you how to make GIFs from sections of videos usin <code>ffmpeg</code>, I think there is not an easier way of maing gifs than this, just a quick command and you are ready to go.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="movie-minimalism-a-documentary-about-the-important-things-https-www-netflix-com-ve-en-title-80114460"><a href="https://www.netflix.com/ve-en/title/80114460" target="_blank">[movie] Minimalism: A documentary about the important things</a></h4>

<p>Directed by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCJ24N4O0bP7LGLBDvye7oCA" target="_blank">Matt D&rsquo;Avella</a>, one of my favourite youtubers, this is a documentary about what is minimalism and how it has impacted the life of a lot of people.</p>

<p>At the core minimalism isn&rsquo;t about owning less stuff for the sake of it, it is about being mindful of the things you own, of acknowledging the motivations you have for buying more stuff and taking control over them.</p>

<p>I think minimalism is rising amongst people because of the conditions in which we live today: never has been a time before in which there were more products being marketed to us than today, the internet revolutionized how marketing was done, allowing more people to be influenced even more effectively into consuming, that added to the image of the ideal life portrayed by the mainstream media, one of extreme wealth and material posessions; the constant reminder that you don&rsquo;t have enough and should earn and consume more only serves to keep people unhappy with what they have.</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 16</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/07/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-16/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/07/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-16/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>After a few week without any serious reading, I decided to finally finish The Omnivore&rsquo;s Dilemma.
Part 4 is about hunting, gathering and gardening food, the least middlemen between you and your food.</p>

<p>Right away I found some points worth discussing, one of the earliest being a remark made that it took ancient hunter-gatherers only about 17 hours a week to hunt and gather enough food for them and their families, compared with the now seemingly universal 40 hour work week it seems that the modern life gives us more things to do and leave us with less time to do them.</p>

<p>Later in that same chapter Michael talks about why eat meat, that something that a lot of animal rights thinkers ask is the following: &ldquo;Is it all right to allow animals to suffer just because they are animals? Isn&rsquo;t that a kind of discrimination?&rdquo;. Followed by this paragraph:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Singer says we have a simple choice to make.
We have to choose between our desire to eat meat and allowing the suffering of animals to continue.
Put it that way and it seems you have no choice.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It is true that put that way it seems everything is black or white, but as Michael says later in the chapter it doesn&rsquo;t take into consideration the domestication of animals, that if we don&rsquo;t raise and eat cattle and chickens they will go extinct as they have evolved to live with us.
It is only in the world of imagination that cows and chickens can live in nature without human intervention, if suddenly all people stopped eating meat and all farms released their livestock into the wild those poor animals would die shortly after as would any group of people born and raised in the city without any experience in the wilderness if suddenly dropped into the amazonian forest without guidance.</p>

<p>But that doesn&rsquo;t mean that animals deserve to suffer so much, even if the suffering associated with the death of an animal is inevitable the one associated with the living conditions isn&rsquo;t; if we stopped treating animals like commodities and products in an industrialized food chain and started treating them like the living thing they are the animal suffering can be greatly reduced at the expense of a small decrease in animal produce supply.
(Unnecessary supply, as the demand for animal products is sustained by marketing driven consumption patterns instilled by corporations that only seek profit, not even the well-being of their consumers).</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="blog-post-choosing-fonts-for-your-data-visualization-https-medium-com-nightingale-choosing-a-font-for-your-data-visualization-2ed37afea637"><a href="https://medium.com/nightingale/choosing-a-font-for-your-data-visualization-2ed37afea637" target="_blank">[blog-post] Choosing Fonts for Your Data Visualization</a></h4>

<p>A post about what makes a font fit for use in charts.</p>

<p>I had never given  fonts any thought, I didn&rsquo;t really understand why there are so many and why would one spend any time comparing fonts looking for the &ldquo;perfect one&rdquo;.
It seems I just was ignorant about what can be different between fonts, this post talks about <em>x-heights</em>, <em>serifs</em>, <em>counters</em> and spacing between numbers.</p>

<p>Seeing those differences so clearly and explained in such detail gave me a new apreciation for fonts, even if I&rsquo;m still not passionate about them now I can understand why some people are.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-are-western-and-japanese-rpgs-so-different-design-icons-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-fjiwn8ixqoi"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fJiwn8iXqOI" target="_blank">[video] Are Western and Japanese RPGs so Different? | Design Icons</a></h4>

<p>A quick (~15 minutes long) story about RPGs, the best genre of videogames, and how some games influenced the distinction between Japanese and western RPGs.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-the-past-we-can-never-return-to-the-anthropocene-reviewed-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-ybgnlkjpga4"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YbgnlkJPga4" target="_blank">[video] The Past We Can Never Return To – The Anthropocene Reviewed</a></h4>

<p>An animation of a section of a podcast. The story of the discovery of the Lascaux cavern and some thoughts about humans in general, a very good video that gets to you in unexpected ways. One of the better things I have seen recently.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="music-youtube-yt-bancamp-bc-猫-シ-corp-palm-mall">[music] [<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kovd7OzcU9s" target="_blank">youtube</a> <a href="https://noproblematapes.com/album/palm-mall" target="_blank">[bancamp]</a> 猫 シ Corp. : Palm Mall</h4>

<p><center><img src="https://f4.bcbits.com/img/a1683187476_10.jpg" width="50%"></center></p>

<p>This album is a must listen, using music to create the feeling of being in a mall full of people, the first 22 minutes of the album are something to experience.</p>

<p>Vaporwave has something for everyone, it&rsquo;s funny how I started listening to it ironically and ended up discovering gems like this, pieces that challenge what you think is possible through music.
To think that listening to some recordings of malls with a faint music playing in the background could make you feel like you are there, immersed in a shopping mall experience striped off of anything unpleasant associated with being actually there is incredible.</p>

<p>Maybe I haven&rsquo;t being exposed to those kind of sounds prior to listening to this, but this being my first encounter with this kind of music gave it a very special place in my heart. A marvel of digital media, and I insist, a must listen.</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 15</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/07/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-15/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/07/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-15/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>This week I tinkered with my laptop&rsquo;s graphic configuration, I messed up and had to spent a day working inside a tty, fortunately I am an avid terminal user and could live without a graphical interface and also the same day, albeit almost at midnight, I could fix the problem.
Now I can use the Nvidia graphics card that came with my laptop and can peek into the PC master race lifestyle.</p>

<p>Also this week is the 15th week in a row that I blog, not bad.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-republicans-finally-support-masks-months-too-late-technewsday-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-twwkc80oexw"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TwwkC80OExw" target="_blank">[video] Republicans FINALLY Support Masks MONTHS Too Late - TechNewsDay</a></h4>

<p>Skip to minute 21:00 until 28:00 for the most interesting part.</p>

<p>A quick reminder that the internet as a whole is a privacy nightmare.
In the video Phil talks about how the new iOS 14 exposed that a lot of apps copy the content of your clipboard when you use them (and some even if you aren&rsquo;t currently using them).
He also mentions how universal clipboard is makes the potential privacy concerns even worse and also some other problems with facial recognition software.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-the-stock-market-is-easy-money-do-this-now-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-fy0clsby3v8"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fy0clsby3v8" target="_blank">[video] The Stock Market is EASY MONEY _ DO THIS NOW</a></h4>

<p>An entertaining video about how current events have sparked a wave of gambling disguised as investing.</p>

<p>Here Graham Stephan shows a few news headlines about how people are buying stocks of bankrupt companies hoping to make profits and how some of those people have succeeded in doing so.
He also mentions how that way of buying stocks is more gambling than investing and how you should avoid following those steps thinking that you will make money.
Never gamble money you can&rsquo;t afford to lose.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-how-to-finish-what-you-start-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-ai8irb7l-jm"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ai8Irb7L_JM" target="_blank">[video] How to Finish What You Start</a></h4>

<p>A video about how limitations can improve one&rsquo;s ability to complete a project one starts.</p>

<p>It gives a few tips about the best ways to impose limitations on a project in order to better the likelihood of completing the project, as too much choice can lead to what is called &ldquo;analysis paralysis&rdquo;.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="music-youtube-yt-bandcamp-bc-windows彡96-gradient-horizont">[music] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b2Iq6AE_Bko" target="_blank">[youtube]</a> <a href="https://windows96.bandcamp.com/album/gradient-horizont" target="_blank">[bandcamp]</a> Windows彡96 : Gradient Horizont</h4>

<p><center><img src="https://f4.bcbits.com/img/a1163286928_10.jpg" width="50%"></center></p>

<p>Windows彡96 is one of the bigger names in the vaporwave space, this album is a perfect example of what vaporwave can be, melancholic yet optimistic, completely sample-free yet still vaporwave.
4th and 5th tracks are my favourite from this album.
Truly worth your time.</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 14</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-14/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-14/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<hr />

<h4 id="video-zoomer-consooomer-gets-red-pilled-on-technology-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-wpep7if6nrs"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WPEP7iF6NRs" target="_blank">[video] Zoomer Consooomer gets Red-pilled on Technology</a></h4>

<p>Luke Smith responding to an email asking him about the intersection between technology and life.</p>

<p>In the video, Luke talks about how being aware of the implications of technology in one&rsquo;s life doesn&rsquo;t translate into having to reject everything modernity has to offer, but that being aware of those implications gives you the opportunity to make decisions that limit the negative impact of technology in your life.</p>

<p>Technology (or anything, really) is not inherently bad but being mindless about it can be detrimental to one&rsquo;s life.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-goth-bridge-rave-what-was-the-cybergoth-dance-party-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-usmh8wawlf8"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=usMH8waWlf8" target="_blank">[video] Goth Bridge Rave: What Was The Cybergoth Dance Party?</a></h4>

<p>The story behind this video:
<center><img src="http://gifs.gifburger.com/385-cybergoth-dance-party.gif" width="50%"></center></p>

<p>How a meme becomes a meme is one of the most difficult things to answer since memes are a thing, so much that I have known about the cybergoth dance party since what seems like all my life on the internet, and yet it is now that I am learning it&rsquo;s story.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s saddening how judgemental can people be without context, how those initial people lacking the context of the original video turned a seemingly wholesome comment section into a dump of hate and mockery and further obscured the probabilities of truly interested people to find it.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="music-youtube-yt-bandcamp-bc-reverb-lite-wδll-flowers-midnight-escapades">[music] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WbLusW7FqN8" target="_blank">[youtube]</a> <a href="https://music.businesscasual.biz/album/midnight-escapades-2" target="_blank">[bandcamp]</a> REVERB LITE / WΔll Flowers : Midnight Escapades</h4>

<p><center><img src="https://f4.bcbits.com/img/a1719475383_10.jpg" width="50%"></center></p>

<p>A masterclass in good vaporwave, a dreamy experience filled with everything that made me fall in love with the genre back in 2016, slowed down vocals, chopped samples, overly repetitive dreamy loops, a retro atmosphere and an overall sound that can&rsquo;t be found anywhere else.</p>

<p><a href="https://music.businesscasual.biz/track/hold-me" target="_blank">~hold me~</a> and <a href="https://music.businesscasual.biz/track/dresser-money" target="_blank">Dresser Money</a> are my favourites from this album, the former having the perfect amount of repetitiveness, beautifully slowed and chopped samples in the first section and ending in a smooth saxophone section to ease the mood; the later completely different without sacrificing the feel, starting with a catchy slowed and down-pitched vocal sample, ending with a loop slowing down into a nightmarish effect, masterpieces.</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 13</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-13/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-13/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>This week was the definition of dead. Here is the only thing worth sharing that I saw this week and the corresponding music recommendation.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="podcast-private-suite-podcast-vapor-memory-interview-https-privatesuitemag-com-podcast-91"><a href="https://privatesuitemag.com/podcast/91" target="_blank">[podcast] Private Suite Podcast : Vapor Memory Interview</a></h4>

<p>This was an incredible find, I didn&rsquo;t know there was a podcast dedicated to vaporwave until <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T1rl3eHMo5E" target="_blank">Vapor Memory uploaded this interview on his channel</a>.</p>

<p>Being the go-to channel to discover vaporwave on youtube, Vapor Memory is a very well known name in the vaporwave community, a name I would say as well known as some of the older and well established vaporwave artists.</p>

<p>Listening to this interview felt incredible, the feeling of discovery when hearing for the first time the voice of someone you know only as their online persona is something like finding money on the street, unexpected but well received.</p>

<p>Loved all the 2 hours of the interview and got some sick new music to listen to.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="music-youtube-yt-bandcamp-bc-チェスマスター-非実体">[music] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4qdT9P195vs" target="_blank">[youtube]</a> <a href="https://dreamcatalogue.bandcamp.com/album/--23" target="_blank">[bandcamp]</a> チェスマスター : 非実体</h4>

<p><center><img src="https://f4.bcbits.com/img/a0736817748_10.jpg" width="50%"></center></p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t have the words to describe the experience of listening to this album, and even if I had I wouldn&rsquo;t want to describe it.</p>

<p>Futuristic, dark, unnerving, listen to this if you are looking for an auditory experience of those characteristics.</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 12</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-12/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-12/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>This week I played <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hellblade:_Senua%27s_Sacrifice" target="_blank">Hellblade: Senua&rsquo;s sacrifice</a>, I was interested in this game because it&rsquo;s an adventure seen through a schizophrenic woman&rsquo;s eyes, there are visual artifacts through the game and voices, friendly and hostile, that whisper, speak and scream to you from all directions, as if they come from inside your mind, all to make you feel immersed in the experience of living as a schizophrenic.
It was a short game but deeply engaging, it truly is a story that is best told through an interactive medium like videogames.
Also there were a lot of nordic folk stories told over the course of the game, a nice plus.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="podcast-not-related-the-origin-of-consciousness-in-the-breakdown-of-the-bicameral-mind-nr"><a href="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/notrelated/S01E01_-_The_Origin_of_Consciousness_in_the_Breakdown_of_the_Bicameral_Mind.mp3" target="_blank">[podcast] Not related! - The Origin of Consciousness in the Breakdown of the Bicameral Mind</a></h4>

<p>An analysis of the Julian Jayne&rsquo;s theory of consciousness exposed in his book with the same title.</p>

<p>The idea that consciousness is not something inherent of human beings but a learned trait, that humans could develop societies, languages, and culture without being conscious is ludicrous, yet with the examples given, the analysis of how the Illiad and the Odyssey were written and a lot of explanation of the implications of those examples the hypothesis makes sense.</p>

<p>You should give this podcast a listen, you can never go wrong listening about theories of consciousness.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-how-did-the-first-language-begin-the-mystery-of-the-pirahã-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-b5lzt42tb20"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B5lzt42Tb20" target="_blank">[video] How did the First Language Begin? The Mystery of the Pirahã</a></h4>

<p>Self explanatory title, an exploration of how languages started and a deep dive into the language of the Pirahã, a tribe in the Amazon.</p>

<p>On the same topic of consciousness, the function languages have in how we think about our environment is not to be ignored. In <em>Not related!</em> Luke Smith says that Jayne&rsquo;s theory  can explain a change in how the inner state of the person is portrayed in both the Illiad and the Odyssey, the former lacking of any reflection of the inner self in the characters, but the inner state being present and explored the later.
In the section about the Pirahã in the video, a relationship between ecology and language structure is made though the lack of recursion and numbers in the Pirahã language, numbers are not needed to be successful in the jungle, and recursion isn&rsquo;t useful in that environment either, as shorter sentences make easier the recovery of information.</p>

<p>Those points can be a link into consciousness, as people didn&rsquo;t need to reflect on their inner state language did not led itself to that end, but as consciousness arose, the language adapted to the environment.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="music-youtube-yt-bandcamp-bc-prismcorp-virtual-enterprises-home">[music] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D6kMLQoJjAw" target="_blank">[youtube]</a> <a href="https://vektroid.bandcamp.com/album/home-complete-edition" target="_blank">[bandcamp]</a> PrismCorp Virtual Enterprises : Home™</h4>

<p><center><img src="https://f4.bcbits.com/img/a0041278514_10.jpg" width="50%"></center></p>

<p>Vaporwave is commonly associated with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4v8mo7mqBiQ" target="_blank">Macintosh Plus&rsquo; Floral Shoppe</a> and if you are aware of vaporwave&rsquo;s existence most probably you have at least seen Floral Shoppe&rsquo;s cover. What it&rsquo;s not often known for outsiders of the genre is that <a href="https://vektroid.bandcamp.com/" target="_blank">Vektroid</a> over the course of her career has released music under a lot of aliases, Macintosh Plus and PrismCorp Virtual Enterprises being two of them.</p>

<p>Home™ is a peculiar experience, it has a virtual reality aesthetic, early computer graphic shapes and assets, old Nintendo 64 and PlayStation one imagery comes to mind also.
Listening to this make you feel like you are in a virtual reality futuristic mansion completely empty and isolated, a strange feeling to experience but something that is worth experiencing.
It&rsquo;s amazing how music can convey experiences so specific through sound alone, Vektroid&rsquo;s discography is filled with amazing pieces as this one and it&rsquo;s unfortunate to think about Floral Shoppe as her only work.</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 11</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-11/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/06/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-11/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>Not much happened this week, I started developing a <a href="https://github.com/masher2/blogdown.vim" target="_blank">vim plugin to manage my blog</a>, read a little and continued with Chef&rsquo;s Table; the 1st episode of the 3rd season had me in tears through the whole episode, it was beautiful seeing Jeong Kwan cooking and sharing her story, my favourite chapter yet.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-joe-rogan-is-wondering-what-i-m-hiding-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-vjx03tgakpu"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vjX03tgAKpU" target="_blank">[video] Joe Rogan is wondering what I&rsquo;m hiding!</a></h4>

<p>Rob Braxman responding to a comment made by Joe Rogan in the june second episode of Joe Rogan Experience in which while talking about mass surveillance Joe express that he has been following Rob Braxman and wonders why is he so concerned about online privacy, &ldquo;what is he hiding?&rdquo;.</p>

<p>After a little bit of background on Rob Braxman he states the importance of online privacy to the individual and explains some of the real risks related to privacy one is already facing.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-the-economics-of-the-art-market-why-this-painting-isn-t-worth-450-million-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-v5souet8uwa"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V5sOuET8UWA" target="_blank">[video] The Economics Of The Art Market - Why This Painting Isn&rsquo;t Worth \$450 Million</a></h4>

<p>If you ever wondered why the high end art market exists and how could anybody pay millions of dollars for a piece of art this video gives you answers. An explaination of the benefits of buying art so expensive and who are the kind of people that benefit from it.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="music-youtube-yt-bandcamp-bc-iacon-不協和音-dissonance">[music] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AkvV43AlvXk" target="_blank">[youtube]</a> <a href="https://iaconofficial.bandcamp.com/album/d-i-s-s-o-n-a-n-c-e" target="_blank">[bandcamp]</a> iacon : 不協和音 Dissonance</h4>

<p><center><img src="https://f4.bcbits.com/img/a4212537612_10.jpg" width="50%"></center></p>

<p>One of my top 3 favourite albums. I can&rsquo;t describe how much I love this.
A nice 80s feeling with perfectly chopped samples and revamped percussion to refine those original songs into something completely new. Truly a vaporwave essential.</p>

<p>The 4th song, <a href="https://iaconofficial.bandcamp.com/track/r-e-t-u-r-n" target="_blank">マRイ·EハTートUをR返Nす</a>, is peak vaporwave, an experience from beginning to end.
Even though all of the songs in this album are top notch, to me this one stands out above the rest.</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 10</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-10/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-10/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>Recently I&rsquo;ve been watching <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chef%27s_Table" target="_blank">Chef&rsquo;s Table</a>, as the name sugests it is about chefs, with each episode being a short documentary about a single chef&rsquo;s history, the restaurants in which they are working and why they are cooking as they are. It is hands down one of the best shows I&rsquo;ve seen.</p>

<p>Dan Barber, the chef featured in the second episode, was the one that most resonated with me; the restaurants he owns revolve around the concept of <em>farm to table</em>, cooking the ingredients as close as posible to the source, all local and sustainable.
He states the impact farming practices have on the flavour or the food and the integrity of the land. Most of the things that he said throughout the episode are things that Michael Pollan noted in The omnivore&rsquo;s dilemma, and seeing a chef doing his best to live up to his convictions is an incredible thing to behold</p>

<p>Other stories that I felt more close to me were the ones of both Francis Mallmann (Argentina) and Alex Atala (Brazil), both started their careers cooking french food, and both tell that in a point of their career a french told them that their food wasn&rsquo;t french food, they could get the taste and the technique and everything else right but the soul of the food would never be french.
That was a point of inflexion that made them realize the importance of the cultural background of the cook in the food that they prepare, all cuisines should be appreciated but the one that one grew up with should be exhalted, as it is an integral part of who one is.</p>

<p>The importance of cultural influence in how people percieve different flavours is captured beautifully by Alex Atala, when comparing the taste of caviar and tucupi (the juice of manioc flour), after expressing that the first time he tasted them he didn&rsquo;t know if he liked those flavours, he says: &ldquo;But if caviar is fancy, and tucupi is not fancy, it&rsquo;s just because someone told me. There&rsquo;s a cultural interpretations of flavors.&rdquo;</p>

<p>After each episode I feel more interested in the food and the ingredients that I haven&rsquo;t experienced here in Venezuela, this show has been more successfull at making me feel a little bit more Venezuelan that any other thing in my life.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-why-facebook-just-paid-400m-for-gifs-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-ffm7tzskcwq"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FfM7tzskcwQ" target="_blank">[video] Why Facebook just paid \$400m for GIFs</a></h4>

<p>An explaination of the motivations that facebook could have had to buy Giphy, this video also raises some privacy concerns that come from that acquisition.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-enjoy-the-cyberpunk-dystopia-of-proprietary-software-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-f5ueuwmlqri"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f5UEuWMlqRI" target="_blank">[video] Enjoy the Cyberpunk Dystopia of Proprietary Software!</a></h4>

<p>Luke Smith ranting about how through proprietary software you are exposed whatever the company that creates that software wants to do, using the current contact tracing feature of iOS as an example.
Not everything is bad though, as free software is a valid alternative, you shouldn&rsquo;t let proprietary software companies take advantage of you because &ldquo;that&rsquo;s the way things are&rdquo; because they aren&rsquo;t.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="music-youtube-yt-bandcamp-bc-calusa-eisenhower-リー地区-cape-coral-jazz-club-1958">[music] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wevAKu5kE0U" target="_blank">[youtube]</a> <a href="https://dmttapes.bandcamp.com/album/cape-coral-jazz-club-1958-dmt-001" target="_blank">[bandcamp]</a> Calusa Eisenhower : リー地区 // Cape Coral Jazz Club 1958</h4>

<p><center><img src="https://f4.bcbits.com/img/a2549125632_10.jpg" width="50%"></center></p>

<p>&ldquo;Let&rsquo;s suppose that you were able every night to dream any dream you wanted to dream&rdquo;.</p>

<p>An album constructed upon samples of Allan Watts.
Allan&rsquo;s voice has something that just works in music, the knowledge he shares with the world, his ideas, everything sounds so mystic yet so real and applicable to daily life.
Hearing an album made around his voice is something I never heard before, I didn&rsquo;t know I needed it until I heard it.</p>

<p>The album is short, with only 20 minutes it could have been a single song, but either having it as background music or listening what Allan has to say is a delightful experience.</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 9</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-9/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-9/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>I&rsquo;m currently into the local sustainable section of <em>The omnivore&rsquo;s dilemma</em>, reading about Polyface farm feels like a dream, it&rsquo;s incredible how that way of farming contrasts with the industrial way of highly scaled monocrop fields.</p>

<p>One of the things that came to my mind whilst reading this section was that automation isn&rsquo;t always synonym with progress, even though the industrial food system has skyrocketed the production of food, it has done so despite the damage it causes to the land and the ecosystem.</p>

<p>It is naive to think that food is food independently from where it comes, plants are living beings and the conditions in which they develop affect how good can they be for us, the same with cow, chicken and fish meat, psychological and physical stress are deeply related with the quality of the meat.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-6-reasons-why-i-choose-to-unschool-my-children-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-yff6bol3hns"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yff6BOl3hns" target="_blank">[video] 6 Reasons Why I Choose to Unschool My Children</a></h4>

<p>An explaination of why a family in New Zealand chose to leave their kids out of school.</p>

<p>Exploring alternatives to mainstream education is always interesting, this in particular I found it a little extreme at first.
The idea of not going to school is excellent as a child, in my experience I would say that most children don&rsquo;t like going to school for anything else than seeing their friends; but as an adult that has gone through that whole system it&rsquo;s another story.</p>

<p>Even though I can see the problems in mainstream education (standardize the teaching for 30+ children in a single classroom, measure only logical-mathematical intelligence over other kinds of intelligence, encourage memorization over comprehension, etc), I am not convinced that <em>unschooling</em> is the best alternative, the main concern it raises is what is an <em>unschooled</em> to do if they want to pursue a career? According to the comments they could get the certifications needed to attend to university or something like that eventually.</p>

<p>I have a degree in statistics and most of the things saw during highschool I dind&rsquo;t feel like I needed them. I can see an <em>unschooled</em> that got interested in mathematics and statistics pursuing a career in the field and have a satisfactory outcome, IMO university isn&rsquo;t that hard if you are truly interested in the themes.</p>

<p>Another thought is that maybe <em>unschooled</em> children wouldn&rsquo;t be likely to pursue traditional careers, as they are exposed to alternative lifestyles through their development they wouldn&rsquo;t necessarily be attracted to the mainstream way of living that depends 100% on earning money to not die of starvation.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-the-strange-world-of-youtube-s-corporate-propaganda-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-vuakzpjeibm"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VUAkZPJeiBM" target="_blank">[video] The Strange World of YouTube&rsquo;s Corporate Propaganda</a></h4>

<p>A video looking into the youtube&rsquo;s creator academy videos, the advice they give and the motivations behind them.</p>

<p>The comparison between the wendy&rsquo;s hot drink video and the youtube creator academy, the idea that the YCA is basically youtube&rsquo;s equivalent of a corporate training video  is very interesting, it shows the power youtube and by extention google, has over the video consumption in the internet, rewarding more a kind of content is a way to control what kind of content is produced.</p>

<p>Another interesting point the video makes, and the one that I find more troubling is how through the YCA youtube presents itself and how it rewards the content being pushed to the platform as &ldquo;a force of nature&rdquo;, and that you have to comply with it or else.</p>

<p>That is a reminder that centralization is a bad thing on the internet, it may be convenient to consume all your content in a single website, but the company behind that website gains more control over what content you consume, the same applies to other types of sites,e.g. google controlling what you can access on the internet and facebook controlling what you are allowed to say online.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="music-youtube-yt-bandcamp-bc-camino-84-yacht-rock-breaks-2">[music] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=81yNdAbu4as" target="_blank">[youtube]</a> <a href="https://music.businesscasual.biz/album/yacht-rock-breaks-2" target="_blank">[bandcamp]</a> Camino 84 : Yacht Rock Breaks 2</h4>

<p><center><img src="https://f4.bcbits.com/img/a0789798331_10.jpg" width="50%"></center></p>

<p>The second and in my opinion the better of the two Yatch Rock Breaks albums of <a href="https://f4.bcbits.com/img/a0789798331_10.jpg" target="_blank">Camino84</a>. A beachy, relaxed album of two songs clocking in 25 and 23 minutes respectively. A journey through funky chill samples and sounds that will transport you to better times.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t let the lenght of those songs scare you, as they are structured as a few mini-songs inside each one, a sudden change of rythm always announce the next section in a smooth transaition, each section more chill and funky than the last.</p>

<p>Personally this is one of my favourite albums and it&rsquo;s a delight to listen from time to time.</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 8</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-8/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-8/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>This week I finished the second part of <em>The omnivore&rsquo;s dilemma</em>, the one about the industrial organic food system.
Not much changes compared to the plain industrial food system, the main difference stands in the lack of chemical fertilizers and pesticides, but the conditions of everything else, from how fields are distributed and harvested to how animals are kept stays the same, factory farms.</p>

<p>The funny thing about this is the history behind some of the organic agribusinesses opearting in the US, in the book <em>Cascadian Farm</em> is mentiontioned:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Cascadian started as a kind of hippie commune in 1972, founded by a fellow named Gene Kahn and his friends. Like other young people at the time, Kahn had the idea of getting back to the land and changing the American food system. Today Cascadian is owned by General Mills, and Kahn is a General Mills vice president. Cascadian doesn’t even grow its own food anymore. Instead the company buys produce from large (organic) industrial farms, many of them monocultures.&rdquo;<br />
<div style="text-align: right">(Michael Pollan – The Omnivore&rsquo;s Dilemma)</div></p>
</blockquote>

<p>It seems like you either die a hero or live long enough to become the villain.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-i-learned-portuguese-in-7-days-part-1-my-method-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-lhcvejeab0e"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lhcvejeAB0E" target="_blank">[video] I Learned Portuguese in 7 Days – Part 1 (My Method)</a></h4>

<p>An accelerated language learning experiment done by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrdWRLq10OHuy7HmSckV3Vg" target="_blank">Nathaniel Drew</a>, this is not the first time he has attempted becoming conversational in a new language in a week as <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fxAaBZNduQs" target="_blank">he already has done so with italian</a>.
I find this method extremely interesting as he has succedded both times.</p>

<p>I have been trying to learn norwegian using duolingo (I think I had a streak of over a year in two different opportunities) but I became bored with it, without input other than where you are learning it becomes monotonous and it&rsquo;s easy to lose your motivation.
I would like to try something like this to fast track my norwegian in the future, maybe writing this here serves as an incentive.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="music-youtube-yt-bandcamp-bc-nano神社-segas-ii">[music] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uhbZZV2r2Pk" target="_blank">[youtube]</a> <a href="https://dmttapes.bandcamp.com/album/segas-ii-dmt-199" target="_blank">[bandcamp]</a> nano神社 (✪㉨✪) - SEGAS II</h4>

<p><center><img src="https://f4.bcbits.com/img/a3082387770_10.jpg" width="50%"></center></p>

<p>This album has no chill, all songs are the perfect blend of funky samples and glitched out ａｅｓｔｈｅｔｉｃｓ.</p>

<p>Sometimes one isn&rsquo;t capable of understand human ingenuity until listening to something like this, vaporwave is a genre built on pushing the limits of what is considered music, and this is a perfect example of that concept.
It may hit you when you are investend in a groove and then it breaks unexpectedly or when trying to predict what comes next just to be surprised by another sound glitch.</p>

<p>My favoutire track form this album, the one that made me discover <a href="https://nanoshrine.com/" target="_blank">nano神社 (✪㉨✪)</a> is <a href="https://dmttapes.bandcamp.com/track/day-after-day-after-day" target="_blank">Day after day after day</a>, a piece that can&rsquo;t be unheard.</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 7</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-7/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-7/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p><a href="/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-6/">Last week</a> I commented some things about the first few chapters of <em>The omnivore&rsquo;s dilemma</em>, this week I finished reading the first part, the one about the industrial food chain, and there are some more things to be said about it.</p>

<p>In chapter 8 the author talks about how the omnivore&rsquo;s dilemma<sup class="footnote-ref" id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup> is solved by culture: One eats what one&rsquo;s parents eat, they eat what their parents ate and so on; through generations cultural eating habits are formed, and those habits are generally sufficient to keep most people healthy.
And how that solution to the dilemma is lost through the industrial food chain, through globalization people are distantiated from their food culture and through supermarkets and processed food they are introduced to a whole range of options that make it more difficult to eat right.</p>

<p>On the topic of food culture it elaborates on the evolution of food habits and touches how food is a central part of what made humans humans, not only in the evolutionary sense<sup class="footnote-ref" id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup> but on the identity of tribes and nations.</p>

<p>The first part of the book ends with some facts about fast food that made me think how sad it is that growing up I associated fast food, processed food and snacks with progress and how still today there are lots of people that think that way, when instead we should be exalting the ability to eat whole foods; we are giving up our health and future to a destructive food system with really powerful marketing.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="blog-post-managers-turn-to-surveillance-software-always-on-webcams-to-ensure-employees-are-really-working-from-home-https-www-washingtonpost-com-technology-2020-04-30-work-from-home-surveillance"><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/04/30/work-from-home-surveillance/" target="_blank">[blog-post] Managers turn to surveillance software, always-on webcams to ensure employees are (really) working from home</a></h4>

<p>An article about how companies shifting to remote work due to the quarantine are forcing surveillance software to their employees.</p>

<p>The article talks about two companies that make software targetted at companies with remote employees, one is some kind of &ldquo;virtual office&rdquo;, problematic because it forces a restrictive working paradigm on their remote employees under the excuse that working at home can be lonely, when the underlying motivation is to keep control over the employees, removing their ability to manage their own time. BTW, I have always worked from home, so it&rsquo;s natural that I am hostile against working in an office.</p>

<p>The second company they mention is just evil, the software they sell can be installed silently, it takes constant screenshots, logs all activity on the computer and then sends reports of the activity to a manager; it is 1984 levels of surveillance in real life managerial spyware.
This is outraging, I am outraged at the thought of companies existing with such disregard for their employees to the point that they are willing to micromanage them at that ludicrous extreme.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="blog-post-narcissist-decoy-el-cíber-narciso-https-www-antropomedia-com-2016-05-13-narcissist-decoy-el-c-c3-adber-narciso"><a href="https://www.antropomedia.com/2016/05/13/narcissist-decoy-el-c%C3%ADber-narciso/" target="_blank">[blog-post] Narcissist Decoy: el cíber-narciso</a></h4>

<p>An article about the practice in social media of uploading a selfie accompanied with a caption that doesn&rsquo;t relate to the picture as a mean to ease the presentation of oneself in a narcissistic manner.</p>

<p>It is not a critique but a examination of the practice.
As most of the people I know and follow in social media incur (and even I have in more than one oportunity) in what they call a &ldquo;narcissist decoy&rdquo;, it is interesting to note one&rsquo;s seemingly unconscius behaviours.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="music-youtube-yt-bandcamp-bc-地球-ジャングル">[music] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=66VNx4ZCIkk" target="_blank">[youtube]</a> <a href="https://hiraeth-records.bandcamp.com/album/-" target="_blank">[bandcamp]</a> 地球 : ジャングル</h4>

<p><center><img src="https://f4.bcbits.com/img/a1140176241_10.jpg" width="50%"></center></p>

<p>Made by the legendary <a href="https://catsystemcorp.bandcamp.com/" target="_blank">猫 シ Corp.</a>, an adventure through your thoughts and through the forest.
Ambient vaporwave blending itself into forest sounds.
Only two songs of around 15 minutes each but really worth a listen, just play it in the background when you are doing something and be teleported to another reality.</p>
<div class="footnotes">

<hr />

<ol>
<li id="fn:1">The idea that because we can eat basically anything the choice of what food is best for us is extremely difficult.
 <a class="footnote-return" href="#fnref:1"><sup>[return]</sup></a></li>
<li id="fn:2">Richard Wrangham&rsquo;s <em>Catching fire: How cooking made us human</em> is a good read about how controling fire and cooking food might be what made possible the enlargement of the brain and lead to the homo sapiens.
 <a class="footnote-return" href="#fnref:2"><sup>[return]</sup></a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 6</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-6/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/05/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-6/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>I have been reading <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Omnivore%27s_Dilemma" target="_blank"><em>The omnivore&rsquo;s dilemma</em> by Michael Pollan</a> lately, the book is a deep dive into how food is produced.
It is divided into 4 parts, each one about a way of producing food (Industrial, industrial organical, local sustainable and hunter-gatherer).
I am currently at chapter five, still inside the industrial portion of the book and I can tell you it has been unexpected, I had some knowledge about how industrial food is farmed (or more appropiately, manufactured) but there are some things that I find extremely amusing: how, at least in the USA as the book has only talked about it and I don&rsquo;t know if it applies to any other country, the industrial food system is mostly designed around corn, makig it so cheap that all farmers lose money growing it, yet they can&rsquo;t grow any other crops because corn is the only thing bought around their farms and only corn is subsidized.</p>

<p>Another point that is made through the first four chapters is that the industrial food system doesn&rsquo;t necessarily result in cheaper food for the people, only in cheap food made <em>from</em> corn or soy, i.e. soft drinks and snacks.</p>

<p>Here is an exceprt from the book that summarizes one of the main problems of the industrial food system:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>A food chain in nature helps us understand who eats what (or whom). But the food chain that feeds most Americans is anything but natural. The industrial food chain that supplies our supermarkets stretches thousands of miles and has dozens of different links. It’s a chain that’s powered by oil and gasoline and controlled by giant corporations. It’s a chain that separates us from our food and keeps us from knowing what it really is we’re eating.</p>
</blockquote>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-what-face-masks-actually-do-against-coronavirus-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-p27hrclmf2u"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P27HRClMf2U" target="_blank">[video] What face masks actually do against coronavirus</a></h4>

<p>Where I live face masks are enforced when going out, but the great majority of people in the street have DIY masks, that was a stress factor for me when going out to do grocery shopping because I thought that wearing those masks is like wearing nothing as common fabrics don&rsquo;t serve as a barrier for the majority of particles that are expelled from our mouths as we cough, sneeze or even talk.</p>

<p>This video besides explaining that it is true that DIY face masks don&rsquo;t protect nearly as much as surgical masks, they are good enough if used in conjuction with social distancing and hand washing.
Sometimes one just needs someone well versed in the field to ease one&rsquo;s preoccupations.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-the-hippest-internet-cafe-of-1995-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-iwssrvjgpqc"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iWssRVJgPqc" target="_blank">[video] The hippest internet cafe of 1995</a></h4>

<p>A short video about one of the first internet cafes back in 1995.
It is interesting to see how the world has change in over 25 years, from a time where few people know what even the @ symbol was to now, where if you don&rsquo;t have email nor a smartphone you can be denied a lot of oportunities.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="music-youtube-aqvarivs-yt-bandcamp-aqvarivs-bc-underwater-computing-δqvδrivs">[music] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cAMt0YJ0MyA" target="_blank">[youtube]</a> <a href="https://underwater-computing.bandcamp.com/album/qv-rivs" target="_blank">[bandcamp]</a> Underwater Computing : ΔQVΔRIVS</h4>

<p><center><img src="https://f4.bcbits.com/img/a2553916013_10.jpg" width="50%"></center></p>

<p>Another underwater vaporwave journey, a compilation of songs from <a href="https://underwater-computing.bandcamp.com/" target="_blank">Underwater Computing</a> vaporwave label.
Just under one and a half hours of incredibly smooth sounds and watery aesthetics this is one good compilation</p>

<p>The 7th song <a href="https://underwater-computing.bandcamp.com/track/--72" target="_blank">バーチャルボーイＡ ｔ ｓ ｕ - 海の波のように</a> is out of this world, I think it samples a song from Yu-gi-oh! Forbidden memories but I could be wrong here. Really good stuff that you should check out if you are in for an adventure.</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 5</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/04/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-5/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/04/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-5/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>The last two weeks have been abysmal, my internet connection went back on mid-week and I haven&rsquo;t spent much time doing anything other than working. I barely managed to find something worth sharing but here we are, still showing up.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-negative-oil-prices-explained-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-ygdqzorz4nm"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YGDQzORZ4NM" target="_blank">[video] Negative Oil Prices Explained.</a></h4>

<p>One of the most interesting things I have seen recently. A comprehensive explanation of how derivatives work, the factors that caused oil prices (for a single contract) to become negative recently, what does it mean for the oil industry and why you will never get paid for refueling your car.</p>

<p>This video answered all the questions I had about that event, it was so strange seeing all the headlines and commentaries about the oil prices going down like crazy and not understanding why something like that can happen or how could that affect us. After watching this I retrospectively see all the memes about negative oil prices and can understand the misconceptions in which those are founded. There is a lot to gain from this video, absolutely recommended.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-the-stock-market-vs-the-economy-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-0ecqdapjjv0"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0ECqDaPjjV0" target="_blank">[video] The Stock Market vs. The Economy</a></h4>

<p>A data backed explanation of the differences between how the economy and the stock market behave in conjunction. It serves to answer the question &ldquo;If the economy seems to be collapsing, why does the stock markets keep growing or is not as affected as I think it should be?&rdquo;.</p>

<p>It can be a little technical at times but it&rsquo;s accessible if you are not afraid of looking up terms you don&rsquo;t understand.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-can-anyone-learn-to-code-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-ourkqoiabck"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OURKqOIAbck" target="_blank">[video] Can Anyone Learn to Code?</a></h4>

<p>This is more on the motivational side of things rather than educative. Even if the video is about code, &ldquo;code&rdquo; can be replaced with any other discipline or skill without it losing relevance. Proficiency is all about practice, even if someone can become proficient in something more easily than you are you don&rsquo;t have to be discouraged by it, because with enough time and effort invested any skill or discipline can be learned.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="music-irresistible-vaporwave-mix-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-mnjagh8pr4q"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mnjaGH8PR4Q" target="_blank">[music] Irresistible (Vaporwave mix)</a></h4>

<p>If you could distil classic vaporwave to it&rsquo;s essence this is what it would sound like.</p>

<p>A carefully made mix by the one and only <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/Kurdtbada/" target="_blank">Kurdtbada</a>, one of my favourite youtube channels, dedicated mostly to upload vaporwave mixes, all of Kurdtbada&rsquo;s uploads are excellent, but this one in particular has a feeling that reminded me of when I first started listening to vaporwave. A retro aesthetic transmitted solely through sound, an adventure on it&rsquo;s own. Close your eyes, let yourself go and experience vaporwave at its finest.</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 4</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/04/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-4/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/04/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-4/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>Another slow week with nonexistent home internet, using my phone hotspot to at least get some work done. Magically I managed to find content to share here.</p>

<p>Also I found a topic I want to delve deeper into but I need real internet to flesh it out, stay tuned in the next few weeks.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="blog-post-how-dangerous-is-climbing-mount-everest-everest"><a href="https://www.alexcookson.com/post/how-dangerous-is-climbing-mount-everest/" target="_blank">[blog-post] How dangerous is climbing Mount Everest?</a></h4>

<p>A post exploring climbing expeditions to Mount Everest with some nice visualizations.
The post is focused on <code>R</code> code but the visualizations and analysis are accessible to anyone, don&rsquo;t let the code discourage you from reading it.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-are-plant-based-meats-actually-sustainable-impossible-burger-beyond-meat-plant-based"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=snMaXpZc_Mg" target="_blank">[video] Are plant-based meats actually sustainable (Impossible Burger &amp; Beyond Meat)</a></h4>

<p>A video essay about the environmental impact of beef operations (i.e. factory farming) and how they compare to plant based meats like Beyond Meat or Impossible. This comparison isn&rsquo;t trying to devilize the meat industry in favour of plant based alternatives, but to show the damage that industrialized animal meat production does to the environment and some ways that it can be reduced.</p>

<p>&ldquo;A market based solution will never single-handedly solve a market created problem&rdquo;</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-macau-the-story-of-china-s-golden-child-macau"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O5fM1ANvAd4" target="_blank">[video] Macau - The Story of China&rsquo;s Golden Child</a></h4>

<p>A short documentary about Macau, an former portuguese colony now special administration region of China, the &ldquo;gambling capital of the world&rdquo;. It explores the history and development of the region and shows similarities and differences with Honk Kong.</p>

<p>The documentary is half and hour long and very interesting. The topic is not something I am particularly drawn to but nevertheless it was time well spent.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="music-youtube-dinersclub-yt-bandcamp-dinersclub-bc-waterfront-dining-diners-club-part-2">[music] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pRQYcfHDyyA" target="_blank">[youtube]</a> <a href="https://adhesivesounds.bandcamp.com/album/diners-club-part-2" target="_blank">[bandcamp]</a> waterfront dining - Diners Club - Part 2</h4>

<p><center><img src="https://f4.bcbits.com/img/a2952361331_10.jpg" width="50%"></center></p>

<p>My favourite album from my favourite vaporwave artist. All songs are collaborations between waterfront dining and other vaporwave legends. A masterpiece filled with banger after banger.</p>

<p>If you aren&rsquo;t convinced yet at least listen to the last song, <em>lovesick boogeyman (feat. 空手王)</em>, the mood it conveys can&rsquo;t be described with words.</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 3</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/04/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-3/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/04/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-3/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>I avoid almost all covid19 information out there in order to mantain my chill during this time, it is stressful enough to have to go outside to buy groceries surrounded by people that don&rsquo;t take this situation seriously, I don&rsquo;t need all my remaining time to be consumed by stress related to unactionable information. Getting that out of the way, this week I read something about why people shouldn&rsquo;t be doing data visualizations lightly with covid19 data, a must read if you work with data and want to make something pretty to display in your linkedin profile.</p>

<p>Also I will be recommending music weekly because I think sharing it here will have a higher probability of people actually listening to it than sharing it through <a href="https://instagram.com/masher__2" target="_blank">my instagram</a>.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="blog-post-why-i-m-not-making-covid19-visualizations-and-why-you-probably-shouldn-t-either-https-www-williamrchase-com-post-why-i-m-not-making-covid19-visualizations-and-why-you-probably-shouldn-t-either"><a href="https://www.williamrchase.com/post/why-i-m-not-making-covid19-visualizations-and-why-you-probably-shouldn-t-either/" target="_blank">[blog-post] Why I’m not making COVID19 visualizations, and why you (probably) shouldn’t either</a></h4>

<p>A post about the potential negative impact visualizations of the COVID19 pandemic could have.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s not a gatekeeping post about why nobody should do any project regarding the COVID19, but an explaination of the complications in the models and visualizations about the disease and why it can be problematic to share yours with the public.</p>

<p>This in an excerpt from the article that summarizes it:</p>

<blockquote>
<p><em>If you’re thinking about doing a project with COVID19 data, first ask yourself: Can I do better than these huge organizations [FT, NYT, WHO] and the top experts on public health? If not, then promote the work of experts instead of creating your own inferior and potentially harmful version. With the stakes as high as they are, and with the state of the current data on the outbreak, this kind of reporting should be left to the experts, not used as a fun weekend coding project.</em></p>

<p>[&hellip;]</p>

<p><em>However, if you just think the data is interesting, and want to practice your analysis or visualization skills, there’s no harm in downloading some data and working on it on your local machine. The danger comes when you decide to share that with the public.</em></p>
</blockquote>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-how-modern-families-increase-social-inequality-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-hsmayunzyxe"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hSmAYUnZyxE" target="_blank">[video] How modern families increase social inequality</a></h4>

<p>A video exploring some aspects of how modern families are structured. To me the most interesting part starts at 08:45 where some statistics around family structure are shown and middle and lower class families are compared.  The differences in family structure between middle and lower class families impact strongly how their children are raised and eventually it has the potential to keep increasing the social and economic inequality between those groups.</p>

<p>Getting out of poverty is not as easy as some say, it is not only about money or motivation to do something, it is heavily affected by the environment children are raised. I remember I read an article about it quite some time ago but I couldn&rsquo;t find it, I will add it to a subsequent ITISTW entry as soon as I find it again.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-the-benefits-of-social-isolation-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-nxqe9bpdw5e"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nxQe9bPDW5E" target="_blank">[video] The Benefits of Social Isolation</a></h4>

<p>Self explainatory title, this quarantine doesn&rsquo;t have to be completely bad, there are some benefits you can draw from it. If you are fortunate enough to be reading this I am pretty sure you can get something positive from watching this video. Make this an oportunity to better yourself, don&rsquo;t be giving your life away only to mindless content consumption (not that it is bad, but don&rsquo;t spend all this free time doing it).</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="music-youtube-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-guuw8p13wsm-bandcamp-https-aut2m-bandcamp-com-album-area-aut2m-area">[music] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GuUw8p13wsM" target="_blank">[youtube]</a> <a href="https://aut2m.bandcamp.com/album/area" target="_blank">[bandcamp]</a> AUT2M : Area</h4>

<p><center><img src="https://f4.bcbits.com/img/a1940628821_10.jpg" width="50%"></center></p>

<p>A beautifully made electronic album, ambiental, mysterious, dark, calming, a journey on it&rsquo;s own. I actually listened to this a few weeks ago but it is so good that I needed to share it here.</p>

<p>The second song, Blue, it&rsquo;s an absolute banger. Be ready to get into the underwater electronic scene.</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 2</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/04/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/04/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-2/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>This was a slow week, between my internet being at the absolute worst speed possible and almost all my free time spent playing Digimon Story: Cyber Sleuth (DSCS) on my Nintendo Switch I didn&rsquo;t manage to find much, nontheless here are a few interesting things that I thought worth sharing.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="blog-post-it-s-collapsing-violently-coronavirus-is-creating-a-fast-fashion-nightmare-https-www-gq-com-story-coronavirus-fast-fashion-dana-thomas"><a href="https://www.gq.com/story/coronavirus-fast-fashion-dana-thomas" target="_blank">[blog post] &ldquo;It&rsquo;s collapsing violently&rdquo;: Coronavirus is creating a fast fashion nightmare</a></h4>

<p>An interview with Dana Thomas about the impact of coronavirus in the fast fashion industry.</p>

<p>It is incredible to see how the fast fashion industry operates and how people are oblivious about how everything is made. The globalized system makes it appear as if everything is made out of thin air and nothing could be farther from the truth. The manufacture of clothes is one of the few things that can&rsquo;t be automated, and the compulsory desire for cheap clothing  in gargantuan quantities has made the clothing industry an industry that can only survive due to modern day slavery.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-food-waste-causes-climate-change-here-s-how-we-stop-it-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-1mpfeesem-4"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1MpfEeSem_4" target="_blank">[video] Food Waste causes Climate Change. Here&rsquo;s how we stop it</a></h4>

<p>A video essay about the problem of food waste.</p>

<p>The video shows some key factors that affect the quantity of food that becomes waste in each stage of the supply chain. One of the most shocking is the expiration date in some of the food, an arbitrary date made mostly to add a sense of urgency for the consumer to buy the product, not necessarily because the food goes bad after that date.
It also shows some possible actions to mitigate the food waste in some stages.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="blog-post-pokémon-is-fine-but-digimon-story-cyber-sleuth-is-one-of-the-best-monster-rpgs-you-can-play-https-kotaku-com-pokemon-is-fine-but-digimon-story-cyber-sleuth-is-one-1839230688"><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-is-fine-but-digimon-story-cyber-sleuth-is-one-1839230688" target="_blank">[blog post] Pokémon is fine, but Digimon Story Cyber Sleuth is one of the best monster RPGs you can play</a></h4>

<p>A commentary piece on what makes DSCS so good.</p>

<p>I am an avid Digimon fan and I love JRPGs, I had been waiting for a Digimon RPG for ages since I played Digimon World: Dawn on my Nintendo DS but DSCS and its successor came out on the PSvita; the PS exclusives don&rsquo;t interest me and buying a console just for two games is not a sound financial decision, so I believed I wouldn&rsquo;t be able to play those games, until a few months ago when Digimon Story Cyber Sleuth Complete Edition was announced for the Switch, only a new Metroid announcement could have had me more hyped than a Digimon one, specially this one with the two games in the same package.</p>

<p>I was going to get a physical copy but when I was ready to buy it life happened and a few weeks later the covid-19 got us all trapped inside our homes. Fortunately it was on 30% off in the e-shop a couple weeks ago and I didn&rsquo;t think twice about it.
There is something in getting your favourite digimon in a team and beating other digimon in turn based battles that I can&rsquo;t describe, it&rsquo;s just everything I need.</p>

<p>This game is an absolute gem, If you have a Switch you should check this out. Or at least read the post if you can&rsquo;t understand why someone could prefer Digimon over Pokémon.</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 1</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/03/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/03/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>I had been planning to blog more but I haven&rsquo;t had the motivation to do so, so instead of focusing all my mental energy into a single topic that I just didn&rsquo;t have so much to talk about or doing a project that really wasn&rsquo;t as fun as I thought it could be I will be sharing here a few interesting things (and my comments on some of those things) that I have seen on a weekly basis (hopefully).</p>

<p>I have some strong opinions about the global system that we live in and those opinions will leak through my commentaries on these links, I hope you enjoy it.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="blog-post-all-numbers-are-made-up-some-are-useful-https-vicki-substack-com-p-all-numbers-are-made-up-some-are"><a href="https://vicki.substack.com/p/all-numbers-are-made-up-some-are" target="_blank">[blog post] All numbers are made up, some are useful</a></h4>

<p>An article about how every number that we consider as a true representation of reality or as truth itself is wrong, not necessarily bad, but wrong; some because of the concepts they represent are ill-defined or simply because of the limitations of our understanding of the matter in question.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-how-exxonmobil-controls-our-lives-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-aipwkhbr9wi"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AiPWKHBR9wI" target="_blank">[video] How ExxonMobil controls our lives</a></h4>

<p>An interesting video about the environmental damage ExxonMobil has done and it&rsquo;s complete disregard for everything except profit. There is something called the &ldquo;resource curse&rdquo; that says that &ldquo;the greater a country&rsquo;s dependence on oil and mineral resources, the worse its [economic] growth performance&rdquo;.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-growing-roots-this-farmer-is-taking-root-on-your-rooftops-discovery-on-viddsee-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-vprysy3qtvs"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vPRySy3Qtvs" target="_blank">[video] Growing Roots - This Farmer Is Taking Root On Your Rooftops // Discovery on Viddsee</a></h4>

<p>A small documentary of some urban farms in Singapore.</p>

<p>The recent need for locally sourced food has become mainstream due to the age of information that we currently live in; the abstraction of the food industry, the industrialized aggriculture, could be installed as the de-facto way to obtain food due to the fact that the information wasn&rsquo;t as readily available to the people in general as fast as it is now, the people could only see how the food was cheaper and more available without even thinking about what was better for the environment or even for the human itself.
The video shows some ways that the people in Singapore have found to get out, at least in some part, of the illusion of the globalized food system. You can&rsquo;t optimize the ecosystem for economic growth.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-roads-should-be-abolished-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-gebqnoid-7a"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=geBQNOid_7A" target="_blank">[video] Roads should be abolished!</a></h4>

<p>Luke Smith ranting about roads, explaining how roads affect the development of urban areas and how having a car became almost mandatory because of them.</p>

<p>Because of what he exposes there one could see why food deserts exists in USA and how that has impacted indirectly the ability of a portion of their population to get out of poverty.
Also mentions how turism is an idea void of meaning because when people travel they think they are learning about the world when most of the time they are having the same experiences at home but superficially different. Interesting stuff.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="video-you-ll-never-go-wrong-choosing-independence-neets-rule-wagies-drool-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-lrvmfx4ewi0"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LRVmfx4EWI0" target="_blank">[video] You&rsquo;ll never go wrong choosing Independence! (NEETs rule, Wagies drool!)</a></h4>

<p>Luke Smith talking about how he aproaches most of his decisions, and how the system, building on top of the abstraction of independence (i.e. money) has made everyone too much dependent on the system itself, and it&rsquo;s when the system fails that the dependence and the limitations it imposes on the people becomes obvious.</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Writing a data pipeline in R for streaming tweets</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2019/11/writing-a-data-pipeline-in-r-for-streaming-tweets/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2019/11/writing-a-data-pipeline-in-r-for-streaming-tweets/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>Inspired by <a href="https://www.datacamp.com/community/tutorials/building-a-tweet-etl-pipeline-using-r" target="_blank">this datacamp post</a> and the current events happening in Chile I decided to give it a try to make my own version of a tweet streaming script, with the intention of using it when another event of that magnitud happens and maybe getting some useful insights then, or maybe not, at least I had fun while doing this.</p>

<h1 id="setting-up-the-structure-of-the-script">Setting up the structure of the script</h1>

<p>The first thing I did was plan how to structure the script. I decided to structure separate the process in three functions, one for each letter of ETL (imaginative, ikr). The whole script would look like this:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-r" data-lang="r"><span style="color:#75715e"># Extract</span>
get_tweets <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">function</span>() {}

<span style="color:#75715e"># Transform</span>
transform_tweets <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">function</span>() {}

<span style="color:#75715e"># Load</span>
load_tweets <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">function</span>() {}

main <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">function</span>() {
  get_tweets()
  transform_tweets()
  load_tweets()
}

<span style="color:#75715e"># Run everything</span>
main()</code></pre></div>
<p>I won&rsquo;t be updating the full script in-post as it would occupy too much space, you can look at the finished product <a href="https://github.com/masher2/twitter-etl" target="_blank">here in this github repo</a>.</p>

<h1 id="connecting-to-the-twitter-api-and-streaming-the-tweets">Connecting to the twitter API and streaming the tweets</h1>

<p>After designing the script it is time to start filling those empty functions, I started with the streaming of tweets as it is the logical first step.</p>

<p>To properly use the <code>rtweet</code> package one must create a new app in the twitter developer options, find the keys and secrets and store them somewhere, after that tedious process is done I store the account and access keys/secrets into the <code>.Renviron</code> file, which ended up like this:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-r" data-lang="r">TW_CONSUMER_KEY<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;wow&#39;</span>
TW_CONSUMER_SECRET<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;so secret&#39;</span>
TW_ACCESS_TOKEN<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;much private&#39;</span>
TW_ACCESS_SECRET<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;wow&#39;</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Then creating the token for the session becomes super easy and portable:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-r" data-lang="r">token <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> rtweet<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>create_token(
  app <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;app&#39;</span>,
  consumer_key <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">Sys.getenv</span>(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;TW_CONSUMER_KEY&#39;</span>),
  consumer_secret <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">Sys.getenv</span>(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;TW_CONSUMER_SECRET&#39;</span>),
  access_token <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">Sys.getenv</span>(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;TW_ACCESS_TOKEN&#39;</span>),
  access_secret <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">Sys.getenv</span>(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;TW_ACCESS_SECRET&#39;</span>)
)</code></pre></div>
<p>Writing the body of the <code>get_tweets</code> function was easy too, it ended up being just a wrapper around <code>rtweet::stream_tweets</code> creating a unique filename for the stream data and returning it to use it in the next step. I decided to go with that approach because there is no way (at least that I found) to call functions directly to the messages received, wich could be nice to load data to the database in real time, but whatever, we don&rsquo;t need real time data in the database anyway.</p>

<p>Here is how <code>get_tweets</code> turned out:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-r" data-lang="r">get_tweets <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">function</span>(keys, timeout <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#ae81ff">600</span>, raw_data_dir <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;raw_data&#34;</span>) {
  filename <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">file.path</span>(
    raw_data_dir,
    <span style="color:#66d9ef">paste0</span>(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;stream_&#34;</span>, <span style="color:#66d9ef">format</span>(<span style="color:#66d9ef">Sys.time</span>(), <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;%Y%m%d_%H%M%S&#34;</span>), <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;.json&#34;</span>)
  )
  rtweet<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>stream_tweets(
    q <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> keys,
    timeout <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> timeout,
    parse <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">FALSE</span>,
    file_name <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> filename,
    verbose <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">TRUE</span>
  )

  filename
}</code></pre></div>
<h1 id="parsing-the-streams">Parsing the streams</h1>

<p>After the E was done, it was turn for the T portion. The function reads the tweet data from the file we stored the stream in and then process it.</p>

<p>There is a bunch of data that comes with every tweet, I thought about saving it all but after a first look I realized that there are some fields that I don&rsquo;t consider important with the intention of analyzing what the people is saying about a current live event; so I just deleted the retweets, kept only the tweets that were in spanish, processed the tweet content and the quoted content, removed duplicated tweets and returned the parsed dataframe.</p>

<p>The variables that I considered important for that specific use case were:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>created_at</code>: time is always important.</li>
<li><code>screen_name</code>: to see which users tweeted the most and what.</li>
<li><code>content</code>: self explainatory.</li>
<li><code>source</code>: from which device are the people tweeting from.</li>
<li><code>location</code>: where are the people tweeting from.</li>
<li><code>quoted_user</code>: if the tweet is a quoting somebody, who is the user quoting?</li>
<li><code>quoted_content</code>: what did the other user tweeted (twote?) about?</li>
</ul>

<p>The function ended up like this:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-r" data-lang="r">transform_tweets <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">function</span>(filename) {
  df <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> rtweet<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>parse_stream(filename, verbose<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#66d9ef">FALSE</span>)
  df <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> dplyr<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>filter(df, <span style="color:#f92672">!</span>is_retweet, lang <span style="color:#f92672">==</span> <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;es&#34;</span>)
  df <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> dplyr<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>transmute(
    df,
    date_created <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> created_at,
    user <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> screen_name,
    content <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> text,
    <span style="color:#f92672">source</span> <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#f92672">source</span>,
    location <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> location,
    quoted_user <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> quoted_screen_name,
    quoted_content <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> quoted_text
  )
  df <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> dplyr<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>mutate_at(
    df,
    vars(content, quoted_content),
    <span style="color:#66d9ef">function</span>(text) {
      text <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> text <span style="color:#f92672">%&gt;%</span> 
        <span style="color:#75715e"># coerce to lower case all the words</span>
        stringr<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>str_to_lower() <span style="color:#f92672">%&gt;%</span>
        <span style="color:#75715e"># remove links</span>
        stringr<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>str_remove_all(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;\\s?(f|ht)(tp)(s?)(://)([^\\.]*)[\\.|/](\\S*)&#34;</span>) <span style="color:#f92672">%&gt;%</span>
        <span style="color:#75715e"># remove mentions of other users</span>
        stringr<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>str_remove_all(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;@\\w+&#34;</span>) <span style="color:#f92672">%&gt;%</span>
        <span style="color:#75715e"># remove stopwords</span>
        tm<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>removeWords(tm<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>stopwords(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;spanish&#34;</span>)) <span style="color:#f92672">%&gt;%</span>
        <span style="color:#75715e"># trim all whitespaces</span>
        stringr<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>str_squish()
    }
  )
  df <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> dplyr<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>filter(df, <span style="color:#f92672">!</span><span style="color:#66d9ef">duplicated</span>(content))

  df
}</code></pre></div>
<p>I&rsquo;m not keen on using pipes <code>%&gt;%</code> inside a function&rsquo;s body but in that case it made the processing of the tweets so much legible that I couldn&rsquo;t not use it. Also, I removed the mentions inside the tweets to filter out copypasted responses to multiple people.</p>

<h1 id="loading-to-the-database">Loading to the database</h1>

<p>E and T ready, now for the L. Maybe the easiest part of this ETL is the loading, just connet to the database, write the processed tweets to it and close the connection, easy peasy.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-r" data-lang="r">load_tweets <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">function</span>(tweets, database <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;tweets.db&#34;</span>) {
    conn <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> DBI<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>dbConnect(RSQLite<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>SQLite(), database)
    DBI<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>dbWriteTable(conn, <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;tweet_data&#34;</span>, tweets, append <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">TRUE</span>)
    DBI<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>dbDisconnect(conn)
}</code></pre></div>
<p>Everything seems ready now&hellip;</p>

<h1 id="oh-wait-we-don-t-have-a-database">Oh wait, we don&rsquo;t have a database&hellip;</h1>

<p>After all the work we did to get tweets from the twitter database to ours I have just now realized I have not made a database to store our precious data.</p>

<p>I decided to make a function that sets up the database to avoid writing again those commands in case I decided to delete the file or if any other person would like to use the script. It is super simple, connect to the database, execute the command to create the table and disconnect, the sqlite file is ready.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-r" data-lang="r">setup_database <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">function</span>(database <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;tweets.db&#34;</span>) {
  conn <span style="color:#f92672">&lt;-</span> DBI<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>dbConnect(RSQLite<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>SQLite(), database)
  DBI<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>dbExecute(
    conn,
    <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;CREATE TABLE tweet_data(
</span><span style="color:#e6db74">      tweet_id INTEGER PRIMARY KEY,
</span><span style="color:#e6db74">      date_created INTEGER,
</span><span style="color:#e6db74">      user TEXT,
</span><span style="color:#e6db74">      content TEXT,
</span><span style="color:#e6db74">      source TEXT,
</span><span style="color:#e6db74">      location TEXT,
</span><span style="color:#e6db74">      quoted_user TEXT,
</span><span style="color:#e6db74">      quoted_content TEXT
</span><span style="color:#e6db74">    )&#34;</span>
  )
  DBI<span style="color:#f92672">::</span>dbDisconnect(conn)
}</code></pre></div>
<p>I chose sqlite because I really haven&rsquo;t used it before, the tutorial I was following used sqlite and it truly is easy AF (and fun) to set up.</p>

<h1 id="making-it-a-cli">Making it a CLI</h1>

<p>Now, everything else ready, what can I do to make this script truly a usable piece of software? All my friends know that I am a linux enthusiast and that I love the terminal so much that I ditched RStudio (ahhh, the horror) in favor of nvim and the incredibly made <a href="https://github.com/jalvesaq/Nvim-R" target="_blank">Nvim-R plugin</a> (More on this in a future post), so the obvious path was to make a full CLI for it, luckily for me there is a package that handles that perfectly, <code>optparse</code>.</p>

<p>Using <code>optparse</code> I added the following options to the script:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>--database</code>: defaults to &ldquo;tweets.db&rdquo;, and it is the name od the database to create or connect to.</li>
<li><code>--keys</code>: the search query for the tweets to be stramed, I used the default: &ldquo;#chile,#chiledesperto,#santiago&rdquo; but I intend to make it a mandatory positional argument to increase the flexibility, but that default is ok for our purposes.</li>
<li><code>--initial-setup</code>: if this flag is used just run <code>setup_database</code> and end the script.</li>
<li><code>-f</code> | <code>--force-stream</code>: if this flag is used with <code>--initial-setup</code> stream the tweets afterwards.</li>
<li><code>--raw-data-dir</code>: defaults to &ldquo;raw_data&rdquo;, and its the name of the folder that will hold all the raw data streams.</li>
<li><code>-c</code> | <code>--stream-chunks</code>: the number of times the stream will be done, the default, 5, means that the ETL process will be run five times.</li>
<li><code>-t</code> | <code>--stream-timeout</code>: for how long to run the streaming of tweets, the default is 60, meaning that each stream session will be just one minute long.</li>
</ul>

<p>One thing that I didn&rsquo;t mention is that the ETL process will be run a few times, streaming, processing, loading the tweets and then automatically repeating that for a set number of times, I used the term &ldquo;stream chunks&rdquo; because naming is difficult, but it could be named anything else, that name is not final.</p>

<h1 id="adding-safety-checks-and-logging">Adding safety checks and logging</h1>

<p>We are almost ready, there are a few things that can go wrong with our script:</p>

<ol>
<li>The database file could exist when setting it up, and we could possibly overwrite the data we have.</li>
<li>The raw data directory could not exist and then we could not save the streams to anywhere.</li>
<li>There could be no tweets streamed at all, causing problems in the T and L.</li>
</ol>

<p>For all those problems we have the solution, just check for those conditions before running the body of the corresponding function and we should be safe, there could be more possible problems lurking around but I did not find any more.</p>

<p>Another thing is that we don&rsquo;t actually know what is part of the process is running at any given time, we just know that the console is locked, there could be a slient problem that we are not aware of just because of that, but there is always a solution: <code>futile.logger</code>.</p>

<p>A package that adds logging capabilities similar to the python logging module but in R, what a time to be alive. Just add a few calls to <code>flog.info</code> and <code>flog.debug</code> and we are ready to go!</p>

<h1 id="the-end">The end&hellip; ?</h1>

<p>This is it, the data pipeline, or ETL, I feel that pipeline is just another buzzword used to mistify simple stuff; is ready, now I will play with this someday, maybe add more suff to it, change other things or add a second part to this as a sort of continuation to the idea that led me to creating it in the first place.</p>

<p>The code for this project <a href="https://github.com/masher2/twitter-etl" target="_blank">is here</a>, feel free to give me your feedback on <a href="https://github.com/masher2" target="_blank">github</a>, or <a href="https://twitter.com/Masher_2" target="_blank">twitter</a> :)</p>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Adobe&#39;s Venezuela ban and why libre software is the solution</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2019/10/adobe-s-venezuela-ban-and-why-libre-software-is-the-solution/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2019/10/adobe-s-venezuela-ban-and-why-libre-software-is-the-solution/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On October 7th there was an announcement by the proprietary software giant Adobe to ban al Venezuelan users from using any of its services, not even giving them a refund.<sup class="footnote-ref" id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup> Such announcement came seemingly out of nowhere, following an executive order that doesn&rsquo;t really impede them from having business relationships with individual venezuelan citizens but with the &ldquo;Goverment of Venezuela&rdquo;.</p>

<p>The implications of such action are absolutely detrimental, as most of the creative workers use or depend on Adobe software. That is to be expected though, as Adobe software is practically an industry standard and using anything that isn&rsquo;t from Adobe for that kind of work is not as common as it should be.</p>

<p>So, what should a person trying to earn a decent income in the creative world should resort to after getting prema-banned from using the most common, known, and arguably powerful tools in that area? I know what crosses the mind of any individual in that place: Piracy. But that should not be the way.</p>

<p>Legal and moral affairs apart, piracy should never be an option, it doesn&rsquo;t solve the fundamental flaw that drove the person to it in the first place: the lack of ownership of your software.</p>

<p>Propietary software is owned only by the company that develops it (the proprietor), the copy that resides in your machine or in the browser through yout account is just a leased version of the software, your rights are limited in a way that gives the proprietor absolute power over it and leaves you completely vulnerable to events like this one. Piracy doesn&rsquo;t magically makes you own the software, it only makes your leased copy work (maybe partially) and nothing more, maybe an update will make your copy stop working again.</p>

<p>The best alternative is libre software, software that respects your freedom to use it as you wish, without discriminating against your nationality or your purchasing power. However, libre software is often overlooked by professionals and inexperienced alike for being free of cost, gratis; as if for being free it means it is subpar software.</p>

<p>There is a certain degree of truth that proprietary software is more polished and more featureful, as any project should be if it has the resources of Adobe to maintain it; nevertheless libre alternatives to Adobe software are very well developed and most would be powerful enough for most creatives out there.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=doBR1Ae78aw" target="_blank">Here</a> is a good list of libre alternatives to the Adobe Creative Suite, the video is targeted to linux users but as with most libre software it is available in both Windows and MacOS also.</p>

<p>The point of libre software is not that it is free of cost, the point is that it respects your freedom to use it as you wish, doesn&rsquo;t push the interests of the creators of the software over the interests of its users and will always be transparent in its inner workings.</p>

<p>I want to end this with a quote by Linus from LinusTechTips that resumes everything that is wrong with the current state of software:</p>

<p>&ldquo;So, this sucks for venezuelans but it also kind of has the potential to suck for everyone because this is a reminder of the predicament that we&rsquo;ve gotten ourselves into by creating a world that is dependant on subscription services.&rdquo; - Linus <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tLUALcR2UP4" target="_blank">techlinked</a></p>
<div class="footnotes">

<hr />

<ol>
<li id="fn:1">Only to clarify a few days later that refunds will be offered to venezuelan customers that purchased directly from Adobe and that Behance social media platfrom will continue to be available to them.
 <a class="footnote-return" href="#fnref:1"><sup>[return]</sup></a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Crypto, banking, and spending money in Venezuela</title>
            <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2019/08/crypto-banking-and-spending-money-in-venezuela/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2019/08/crypto-banking-and-spending-money-in-venezuela/</guid>
            <description type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I saw <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aDjww6VAKM8" target="_blank">Universal Access to Basic Finance</a> by Andreas M. Antonopoulos, he starts the talk saying that when visiting Argentina in 2013 for the first time he didn&rsquo;t need to explain &ldquo;why, why bitcoin, why open blockchains, why freedom of finance&rdquo;, that is because all the people in the conference room were interested in the &ldquo;how&rdquo;, because they already understanded the &ldquo;why&rdquo;; those opening words struck me, because here in Venezuela, at least in the kind of environment I am and the kind of people I know, most of us already know the &ldquo;why&rdquo;: The Bolivar Soberano (VES).</p>

<p>After two moneraty reconversions, the first in 2008 removing three zeros, the second last year (2018) removing five more, the VES is nothing more than a bad joke to all of us that remain in the country<sup class="footnote-ref" id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup>. This has led people to use the US Dollar (USD) as a preferred currency as its value stays stable in time compared to the VES.</p>

<p>The problem then arises, food is mostly traded in VES, while goods like smartphones, shoes, and home appliances are preferably traded in USD because holding such an amount of VES would be too risky<sup class="footnote-ref" id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup> or even plain impossible for an individual to obtain (at the time of writing 1 USD ≈ 14000 VES). Add to the problem the insecurity and carrying 500 USD in one&rsquo;s pocket while using public transportation is not something anybody would want to do. Living through this it&rsquo;s only natural to gravitate towards cryptocurrency, even with its volatility, Bitcoin (BTC) is a safer place to hold your money than in VES in a bank account.</p>

<p>Returning to the talk, mr Antonopoulos explains how the banking system keeps the unbanked poor, making their life unnecessarily difficult by denying them basic financial services and sentencing them to cash only and higher fees for things like sending money to someone. For someone like me, who has never left Venezuela and thus has never had the opportunity to open an account in any other currency that is not the Bolivar, spending money in an economy where you either need a suspiciously huge<sup class="footnote-ref" id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3">3</a></sup> amount of VES in your account or need a dangerous amount of USD in your pocket is particularly challenging. That is not the only way though, as many stores (WAY more than those who accept crypto) accept not only VES or cash USD but <a href="https://www.zellepay.com/" target="_blank">Zelle</a>, a payment system between USA bank accounts; I, who am paid mostly in crypto<sup class="footnote-ref" id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4">4</a></sup>, find very difficult spending my money in my home country.</p>

<p>Earlier this week I was in a &ldquo;technology mall&rdquo; in Caracas trying to buy a smartphone for my uncle, I asked in almost every store in that shopping mall asking if they accepted any form of cryptocurrency, something like an hour and more or less 30 stores later I found only one little store that accepted crypto; only one store, in a shopping mall dedicated almost to tech stores, accepted the (arguably) easiest and safest way for a venezuelan who has never left the country to use his money.</p>

<p>Another interesting idea that mr Antonopoulos spoke about was the &ldquo;false idea of safety through totalitarian control&rdquo;, the idea that through massive surveillance of the population all crime will be thwarted, but just as George Orwell depicts in 1984, surveillance only hurts the good people being surveilled, there will always be people powerful enough to avoid surveillance, or at least its consecuences, we as venezuelans know first hand that fact<sup class="footnote-ref" id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5">5</a></sup>.</p>

<p>Nevertheless not everything is bad, as more people talk about crypto more stores will realize there is an oportunity there and will dive into it. I&rsquo;ll keep asking in every store I enter if they accept crypto, and will keep spreading the word of libre software, because if people don&rsquo;t know there is an alternative to the systems they are accustomed to they can&rsquo;t make different choices with how they live their lives.</p>
<div class="footnotes">

<hr />

<ol>
<li id="fn:1">A recurring joke between my friends is that we will become millionaires before the year ends, as we find ourselves holding more hundreds of thousands of VES just for weekly expenses.
 <a class="footnote-return" href="#fnref:1"><sup>[return]</sup></a></li>
<li id="fn:2">This price tag made me laugh, it&rsquo;s amazing seeing the price also in Bolivares Fuertes (VEF) as it quickly became too confusing to compare to after the VES reconversion. Realizing that a ~50 USD faucet is worth 67 billions VEF or 67 trillion plain Bolivares (before the first reconversion) is bewildering. <img src="/posts/crypto-banking-and-spending-money-in-venezuela/faucet.jpeg" alt="675 thousand VES faucet" height="400"/>
 <a class="footnote-return" href="#fnref:2"><sup>[return]</sup></a></li>
<li id="fn:3">Related to the surveillance economy that I touch briefly later in the post.
 <a class="footnote-return" href="#fnref:3"><sup>[return]</sup></a></li>
<li id="fn:4">Not really crypto but <a href="https://uphold.com/" target="_blank">uphold</a>, which is basically crypto
 <a class="footnote-return" href="#fnref:4"><sup>[return]</sup></a></li>
<li id="fn:5">Even though, few people know about ways to reduce the digital surveilance imposed to us, and most of those people prefer convenience over privacy.
 <a class="footnote-return" href="#fnref:5"><sup>[return]</sup></a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
