<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on Jesús Pérez</title>
    <link>https://masher2.github.io/tags/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on Jesús Pérez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://masher2.github.io/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 4</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/04/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/04/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-4/</guid>
      <description>Another slow week with nonexistent home internet, using my phone hotspot to at least get some work done. Magically I managed to find content to share here.
Also I found a topic I want to delve deeper into but I need real internet to flesh it out, stay tuned in the next few weeks.
[blog-post] How dangerous is climbing Mount Everest? A post exploring climbing expeditions to Mount Everest with some nice visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 3</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/04/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/04/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week-3/</guid>
      <description>I avoid almost all covid19 information out there in order to mantain my chill during this time, it is stressful enough to have to go outside to buy groceries surrounded by people that don&amp;rsquo;t take this situation seriously, I don&amp;rsquo;t need all my remaining time to be consumed by stress related to unactionable information. Getting that out of the way, this week I read something about why people shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be doing data visualizations lightly with covid19 data, a must read if you work with data and want to make something pretty to display in your linkedin profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting things I saw this week - 1</title>
      <link>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/03/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masher2.github.io/posts/2020/03/interesting-things-i-saw-this-week/</guid>
      <description>I had been planning to blog more but I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the motivation to do so, so instead of focusing all my mental energy into a single topic that I just didn&amp;rsquo;t have so much to talk about or doing a project that really wasn&amp;rsquo;t as fun as I thought it could be I will be sharing here a few interesting things (and my comments on some of those things) that I have seen on a weekly basis (hopefully).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>